# Miles Abbason Software Engineer

🔀 miles.abbason@gmail.com 🔽 mabbason.com

**in** miles-abbason 😯 mabbason

I am a software engineer with experience developing resilient, and efficient cloud applications. I recently built Seymour, an open-source active monitoring solution for testing API endpoints that is deployed to AWS. Prior to this I founded and grew businesses in the foodservice space, one of which was a franchise across 14 states

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Co-Creator, Software Engineer,** Seymour 🖸

04/2022 - present

Seymour is an open-source globally distributed active monitoring solution deployed to AWS for synthetic API testing.

- Architected and constructed a globally distributed, parallel API test approach using AWS Lambda, EventBridge, SNS, SQS, Elastic Beanstalk, and RDS to simulate HTTP requests to API endpoints and compare responses against test assertions
- Developed the full stack application using Node.js, PostgreSQL, React, Tailwind CSS, and AWS cloud computing services
- Implemented a notification system that triggers messages via email, Slack, or Discord in the event of a failed test
- Reduced system load by leveraging custom message attributes with AWS SNS topic subscription filtering
- Built full system multi-region automated deployment of Seymour Amazon resources by utilizing AWS Cloud Development Kit (CDK) to implement Amazon CloudFormation
- Bypassed CDK deployment limitations by employing AWS SDK at runtime to connect resources across different regions
- Authored comprehensive technical case study, readable at: seymour-active-monitoring.github.io/case-study 🛭
- Collaborated with a remote team of 4 engineers distributed across the US and Europe

### Full Stack Web Developer, Self Employed

02/2021 - 03/2022

Developed open-source software w/technologies such as Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, Docker, JavaScript, React, MongoDB, HTML, and CSS

- Trelloha: Trello-inspired Kanban board for project management built with Node.js, Express, React, Redux, and MongoDB
- Snaggl: RequestBin-like tool for webhooks. Built w/ Node.js, RESTful Express API, React, PostgreSQL

### **Trading Systems Developer,** Crucis Capital, Self Employed

06/2018 - 03/2022

- Created long/short hybrid swing trading program in C# for the NinjaTrader ecosystem
- Authored 20+ financial market indicators and short-term automated trading strategies

#### **Co-Founder,** Pelican's SnoBalls

01/2011 - 05/2018

- Orchestrated company growth from 85 franchisees to 176 and into 7 new states over a two-year span
- Established business infrastructure, processes, and controls + core-process documentation
- Trained 100+ employees and/or franchisees in product, franchise, or business operations
- Founder and Operator: Early-stage franchisee with 2 locations in Durham, NC

## **P** SKILLS

### **Languages and Frameworks**

JavaScript, Node.js, Express, React, Redux, Go, C#, SQL, HTML, CSS, Jest, Handlebars

#### Cloud

AWS: Lambda, SQS, SNS, EventBridge, IAM, RDS, ElasticBeanstalk, CDK, DigitalOcean (Droplets), Heroku

### **Other Technologies**

PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Nginx, Git, Github, HTTP, REST APIs, Docker, Adobe Suite, Linux, Webhooks

## **EDUCATION**

**Software Engineering,** Launch School (Capstone) □

2021 - 2022

**BA Graphic Design,** Cum Laude, California State University East Bay

2007 - 2009